Guide to the Cornell University Publications and Marketing Group records, 1990-2014.
Cornell University Publications and Marketing Group records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Publications and Marketing Group records, 1990-2014.
4-3-3687
Cornell University. University Communications. Publications and Marketing.
6.5 cubic feet.
Photographs, printed material, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Publications on various subjects.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Cornell Publications and Marketing is a full-service marketing communications agency available to the Cornell community, which includes graphic designers, editors, researchers, and writers, and produces print publications on all aspects of the university.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publications on various subjects. Various, brochures, postcards, and other publications produced by the office, most for marketing or informational purposes on Cornell University and its programs. Office files include correspondence and information particularly pertaining to the Cornell identity, logo redesign, and marketing. Also some photographs and slides used for marketing purposes. Files of Deena Rambaum relating to a holiday card for President Rhodes and to one-of-a-kind leather albums created for major university donors.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University -- Public relations.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Publications Produced by University Communications Publications and Marketing
  Publications are ordered by subject. These include brochures, hand outs, books, and other material produced by the marketing group for Cornell and in some cases other organizations.
  - Undergraduate Admissions (Box 1)
    General advertising pamphlets and orientation guides for undergraduate admissions at Cornell; in particular, guides for financing student tuition, living and eating on campus, yearly admissions orientation handbooks,“The Case for Cornell” to “Cornell Bound.” (Handbooks for 2007-2008 and 2012-2013 moved to Handbook collection) Information for transfer students. Class of ‘15 acceptance letter in envelope. Some programmatic brochures, like Merrill Presidential Research Scholars program.
  - Cornell Abroad (Box 1)
  - Telluride Association (Box 1)
  - Cornell's Urban Semester in NYC (Box 1)
    Also a DVD of New York City related press images and design files, DVD-1126.
  - Cornell in Washington (Box 1)
  - Shoals Marine Lab (Box 1)
  - College of Agriculture (Box 1)
    Also includes various related entities. General advertising pamphlets for CALS, the Cornell Cooperative Extension (and its 4-H Youth Development program), the Charles H. Dyson School (an invitation and advertisement for a 2010 “Celebration Dinner). Issues of a Cornell 4-H publication by Marcia Eaves-Sheavly; issues of the CALS News (from 2006, 2007, and 2009); and a draft of “The Twelve Step Plan to Better Success in the Garden” compiled by Charles P. Mazza and dated (in pencil) 5/1/06.
  - College of Art, Architecture, and Planning (Box 2)
    Pamphlets to several large guides that explain what the College of AAP is. Also AAP publications including, the 1996 volume of “The Cornell Journal of Architecture” and a shrink-wrapped copy of Italy Now? Country Positions in Architecture, edited by Alberto Alessi with a foreword by Mohsen Mostafavi.
  - College of Arts and Sciences (Box 2)
    General advertising pamphlets for symposiums and special events; “English Department Newsletters” from 2006 to 2013; various literary publications, including five (mini) volumes of “Poetry in Your Pocket” from 2008 to 2012; several concert calendars; and several celebratory and in memoriam cards from the college. Includes music and performing arts.
  - College of Engineering (Box 2)
    General advertising pamphlets and guides for the undergraduate program at the Engineering School. “Guide[s] for Families” from 2006 to 2008, “Engineering Facts” from 2006 to 2009); four issues of the “Olin Hall News” from 2006 to 2009; issues of “Cornell Engineering Magazine” from 2006 to 2010; issues of the “Engineering College Council” meeting guides from 2006 to 2009; and issues of “Civil and Environmental Engineering Update” magazine from 2006 to 2011. Also a DVD titled "Accelerating Innovation to Transform the Future," DVD-1125.
  - School of Hotel Administration (Box 3)
    Also includes related entities such as the Statler Hotel. General advertising pamphlets and celebration invitations for the Statler Hotel, and under/graduate program advertisements for the Management in Hospitality program and the Culinary Arts program. Student handbooks for “The School for Hospitality Leadership” (2006 to 2010); “Statler Hotel Student Profile” cards (with students’ graduation years—from ’07, ’08, ’11); issues of the “Cornell Hotel School” news magazine (from 2006 to 2008).
  - College of Human Ecology (Box 3)
    General advertising pamphlets and guides for the undergraduate program at the College of Human Ecology (including a showcase of the College’s history titled “1969-1994; The College of Human Ecology at Twenty-Five Years”); issues of the “Human Ecology” magazine - are located at ARP 912; and issues of “Link” magazine (for Human Ecology alumni) are located at ARP 1118.
  - School of Industrial and Labor Relations (Box 3)
    Pamphlets explaining what the ILR School is to pamphlets celebrating its history or alumni to event advertisements.
  - Graduate School (Box 4)
    General advertising and admissions pamphlets for graduate programs at Cornell, including a “Doctoral Dissertation and Master’s Thesis Guide” and two “Code of Legislation of the Graduate Faculty” handbooks.
  - Johnson Graduate School of Management (Box 4)
    Includes annual reports, 2007-2012
  - Law School (Box 4)
  - Weill Cornell Medical College (Box 4)
  - College of Veterinary Medicine (Box 4)
    Includes issues of “Scopes” from 2011 to 2013 and “Annual Reports” from 2007 to 2009. also, the “Cornell Feline Health Center Annual Reports”
  - Alumni Relations, Campaigns, Donor Publications (Box 5)
    Materials regarding alumni events (specifically for “The Tower Club” and the annual reunion) and many, many donation brochures, including various items branded as “Far Above … The Campaign for Cornell”. V holiday greeting cards and reunion or special event advertisements mailed to alumni. There are also reunion guidebooks with event times and descriptions for 2006 to 2009.
  - Various Reports (Box 5)
    General annual reports for Cornell University and its various sub-divisions. General Cornell University annual reports from 2004 to 2012; “Student and Academic Services” annual reports from 2003 to 2011; and “Division of University Communications” annual reports from 2004 to 2007 with the addition of 2011 to 2012. The bulk of the annual reports relates to more specific projects, departments, and interests such as the “Climate Action Plan Summary Report,” “Cornell Information Technologies” plans, Cornell Career Services.
  - General and Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    General advertising for Cornell University and its campuses, ranging from a wide array of pamphlets, about student information, symposiums or special events to Cornell University public initiatives (i.e. on health awareness or campus construction), program guides, such as a few faculty/staff handbooks on “Students in Distress.” Copies of An Optimistic Heart (one hardbound and one softbound), a book of speeches, by Jeffrey Sean Lehman, the eleventh president of Cornell University; issues of “Ezra” magazine from 2009 to 2013; issues of Cornell Football issued “The Crescent” magazine from 2005 to 2009; issues of the “Cornell Chronicle” from 2006 to 2008; issues of Cornell Police issued “Campus Watch” from 2006 to 2010; and academic calendars from 2006 to 2013. American Indian Program, Laboratory of Ornithology, Cornell Adult University, Minority Educational Affairs, Proceedings of the 24th International Workshop on Statistical Modelling. Also items produced by the Marketing Group that are not specifically Cornell related such as items for the Museum of the Earth, Children, Youth, and Families at Risk Program (CYFAR), other local publications.
- Office Files
  - Logos, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Includes Style Manual for University Stationary, information on use of Cornell logos, and designs for a new University logo.
  - Identity Information for other Universities, 1990s-2000s (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Style manuals and identity packets from other institutions.
  - Miscellaneous office items, 1990s-2000s (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Office correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    E-mails regarding logos and signatures.
  - Cornell University Communication Marketing Plan, Lippincott and Margulies, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Plan, recommendations, and presentation regarding the future direction of Cornell's image and marketing.
  - Card designs, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Various images and designs for President Rhodes' holiday cards. Includes many photos of Cornell in winter. Also image used for Dean Call's retirement card
  - Slides by Jon Reis and George Robinson, 1980s-200s (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Photographs of various campus activities and people for potential use in marketing materials. Also some slides of Philadelphia.
  - CDs of photographs., 2000s (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Hi-res photographs of various campus activities and people for potential use in marketing materials. CD-2115 and CD-2116
  - President Skorton travel press kits, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    DVD press kits produced by the office for the Cornell University Delegation Visit to India December - January 2007 and East Asia October - November 2007. DVD-1128 and DVD 1129. Also an alternate label disc for the India trip that is blank, DVD-1130.
  - Assessment of Cornell Research Communications with Recommendations for Improvement, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Produced by Maguire Associates
  - Binder of slides by Wayne Calabrese, 1985 (Box 7)
    Photographs of various campus activities and people for potential use in marketing materials.
  - Binder of slides by Jose Azel, 1986-1988 (Box 7)
  - Pins for Cornell Now and working at Cornell (Box 7)
  - Oversize items and artwork (Map-case Z-23)
    Original artwork for publications, including images of campus, bear mascots, and items for reunion. Also a campus maps and posters for the Cornell Tech Campus in New York City.